{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "The transformer works on principle of ___________ .",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Self-induction",
        "b": "Mutual induction",
        "c": "Both Self-induction and Mutual induction",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "DC supply __________ be used for the transformer.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Can",
        "b": "Connect",
        "c": "Both Can and Connect",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The ratio of secondary induced emf to primary induced emf is known as _________ .",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Voltage transform ratio",
        "b": "Current ratio",
        "c": "Power ratio",
        "d": "All"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Current ratios are in _________ of the voltage ratio.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Direct ratio",
        "b": "Inverse ratio ",
        "c": "Both",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Instrument Transformer are used because",
      "answers": {
        "a": "It is cheap",
        "b": "It provides more safety",
        "c": "It is not practicable to connect instruments and meters directly to the lines in high voltage circuits",
        "d": "Both it provides more safety and it is not practicable to connect instruments and meters directly to the lines in high voltage circuits"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A potential transformer is a ___________",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Step up transformer",
        "b": "Step down transformer",
        "c": "Both Step up transformer and Step down transformer",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A current transformer is a ________",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Step up transformer",
        "b": "Step down transformer",
        "c": "Both Step up transformer and Step down transformer",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In a power transformer, stepping down from 33kV to 11kV on load tap changes is provided along with 16 steps with 1.25% voltage changes in each step and a constant secondary voltage of 11kV is required. If the primary voltage changes from 33kV to 29.5kV then",
      "answers": {
        "a": "The taps should be lowered 5 times",
        "b": "The taps should be lowered 6 times",
        "c": "The taps should be lowered 11 times",
        "d": "The taps should be lowered 9 times"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In a power transformer, stepping down from 33kV to 11kV on load tap changes is provided along with 16 steps with 1.25% voltage changes in each step and a constant secondary voltage of 11kV is required. If the primary voltage changes from 33kV to 34kV then",
      "answers": {
        "a": "The taps should be lowered 4 times",
        "b": "The taps should be raised 4 times",
        "c": "The taps should be raised 2 times",
        "d": "The taps should be raised 1 times"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The current transformer ratio is not equal to the ratio of secondary to primary turns.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "The above statement is false",
        "b": "The above statement is false, because of the effect of magnetizing current",
        "c": "The above statement is true, because of the effect of magnetizing current",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Advantage of using instrument Transformer is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Standard rated instruments may be used easily",
        "b": "It provides safety for operating personal",
        "c": "Both standard rated instruments may be used easily and it provides safety for operating personal",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Potential transformers are carefully designed to ensure",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Minimum variation of voltage ratio with load and minimum phase shift between input and output voltages",
        "b": "Minimum variation of voltage ratio with load and maximum phase shift between input and output voltages",
        "c": "Maximum variation of voltage ratio with load and maximum phase shift between input and output voltages",
        "d": "Maximum variation of voltage ratio with load and minimum phase shift between input and output voltages"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": ""
    }
  ]
}
